Finding Aid for Pi Lambda Theta, Xi chapter (University of Michigan) records, 1922-1983
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Pi Lambda Theta, Xi chapter (University of Michigan) records 1922-1983
Pi Lambda Theta. Xi chapter (University of Michigan)
1 linear foot
861114 Bimu F41 2
University of Michigan chapter of Pi Lambda Theta, a national honorary education association; chapter records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the chapter (donor no. 7088 ) in 1984.
The record group is open to research.
Pi Lambda Theta is a national honorary education association. The organization was originally established as the women's counterpart to the all-male Phi Delta Kappa fraternity. The Xi chapter at the University of Michigan grew out of a local group called the "Girls Education Club" established in 1921. In 1922, the group was accepted by the national association of Pi Lambda Theta as Xi chapter. In the early 1970s, the University of Michigan chapter of Phi Delta Kappa voted to admit women. The following year, Pi Lambda Theta, Xi chapter, voted to include men in their membership. The two groups have since worked closely together, jointly sponsoring such events as seminars.
The record group is arranged into a single series of materials that include membership books, scattered minutes, newsletters and printed materials, photographs, and clippings and scrapbooks detailing chapter activities.
Subjects:
Pi Lambda Theta. Xi Chapter (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Honorary societies.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Aged persons.; African Americans--Women.; Clothing and dress.; Pi Lambda Theta. Xi Chapter (University of Michigan); Rites and ceremonies.; University of Michigan--Honorary societies.; Women--Organizations.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Chapter Records
  - Book of Ceremonies, 1939 and 1976 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1963-1978 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1984 (Box 1)
  - History
    - Projected History/Personal Recollections (Box 1)
    - Xi Chapter History (Box 1)
  - Membership Book
    - 1922-1978 (Includes Constitution) (Box 1)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - 1969-1982 (Box 1)
    - Biennial Council, 1937 and 1981 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters/Printed Materials
    - 1952-1962 (Box 1)
    - 1962-1972 (Box 1)
    - National Office, 1935-1983 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1952/1953-1981/1982 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Initiation, 1976 and Biennial Council, 1975 (Box 1)
    - National Convention, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Picnic 1969 and 50th Anniversary Banquet 1972, color slides (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1923-1977, 2 volumes (Box 1)